Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a very romantic dialogue for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一段非常浪漫的对话。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are at a shop and we are buying jewelry.
今天我们在一家商店里，正在买珠宝。
So of course there are many different types of jewelry and stones.
所以当然有很多不同类型的珠宝和宝石。
So we're going to take a look at all that great stuff.
我们来看看这些好东西。
Let's jump into our dialogue and see what's going on.
让我们进入对话，看看发生了什么。
Good afternoon sir.
下午好，先生。
Is there anything I can help you with today?
今天有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
I'm looking for a nice gift to give my girlfriend.
我在找一份好礼物送给我女朋友。
Our fifth anniversary is next Friday.
下周五是我们五周年纪念日。
Well I would be happy to assist you in choosing the perfect gift for her.
我很乐意帮您为她挑选完美的礼物。
Is there anything in particular that you have in mind?
您心里有什么特别的想法吗？
No, not really.
没有，不太有。
I'm completely at a loss.
我完全没头绪。
Well you can give her a set of pearl earrings or this beautiful heart shaped pendant.
嗯，您可以送她一套珍珠耳环，或者这个漂亮的爱心形吊坠。
What is her favorite gemstone?
她最喜欢的宝石是什么？
That purple one.
那个紫色的。
I'm sorry.
抱歉。
I've never bought jewelry for anyone and I'm kind of nervous.
我从没给任何人买过珠宝，有点紧张。
Don't worry.
别担心。
We specialize in providing our customers a relaxed, pressure free shopping environment.
我们专为顾客提供轻松、无压力的购物环境。
That stone is an amethyst.
那块石头是紫水晶。
We have a range of beautiful amethyst pieces.
我们有一系列漂亮的紫水晶饰品。
Take a look at this bracelet.
看看这个手镯。
It's 18 karat rose gold studded with amethyst and blue topaz.
它是18K玫瑰金，镶嵌紫水晶和蓝托帕石。
It's a great statement piece.
这是一件很抢眼的饰品。
Oh wow.
哦，哇。
That's really pretty.
真漂亮。
Jess would love that.
Jess会喜欢的。
But I was thinking of something a little more delicate.
但我想要更精致一点的东西。
Perhaps a necklace?
也许是一条项链？
We have this beautiful platinum pendant or you could also get her a locket.
我们有这条漂亮的铂金吊坠，或者您也可以给她买个盒式项链坠。
You could also get her a timepiece.
您也可以给她买一块手表。
It's both glamorous and functional.
它既迷人又实用。
If you tell me a little more about your girlfriend, maybe I can help you find something for her.
如果您多告诉我一些关于您女朋友的事，也许我能帮您找到适合她的东西。
Jess?
Jess？
Well, she's very smart.
嗯，她很聪明。
She has a great sense of humor.
她很有幽默感。
She's very feminine.
她很有女人味。
Perhaps you could give her a ring.
也许您可以送她一枚戒指。
Well, actually I was thinking about asking Jess to marry me.
嗯，其实我在想向Jess求婚。
I've just been so nervous.
我一直很紧张。
Well, sir, I believe your fifth anniversary is a great time to propose.
嗯，先生，我觉得五周年纪念日是求婚的好时机。
Okay, I've decided.
好，我决定了。
I'm going to pop the question.
我要求婚了。
Fabulous.
太棒了。
We should look at engagement rings then.
那我们该看看订婚戒指了。
Now that's a whole other section.
那完全是另一个区域了。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
Let's take a look at Language Takeaway.
让我们看看“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
In Language Takeaway, we have a lot of jewelry words and terms for you.
在“语言要点”中，我们为您准备了很多珠宝词汇和术语。
So let's take a look at some of these.
所以让我们来看看其中的一些。
The first one I want to talk about, Marco, is pearl earrings.
Marco，我想谈的第一个是珍珠耳环。
That's right.
没错。
The sales assistant offered a set of pearl earrings.
销售助理推荐了一套珍珠耳环。
So we have earrings that you wear on your ears, right?
所以耳环是戴在耳朵上的，对吧？
Usually girls.
通常是女生戴。
Yes.
是的。
But what about pearl?
那珍珠呢？
Pearls are a kind of decoration that come from inside an animal.
珍珠是一种来自动物体内的装饰品。
The clam is a sea animal that opens up and inside there might be a little pearl.
蛤蜊是一种海洋动物，它张开后里面可能有一颗小珍珠。
It's usually a white or pink, very, very pretty object.
它通常是白色或粉色的，非常非常漂亮的东西。
And we sometimes put them in earrings or on a necklace.
我们有时把它们放在耳环或项链上。
That's right.
没错。
So a set of pearl earrings are earrings that have this little rock or this little marble
所以一套珍珠耳环就是耳环上有这种小石头或小珠子
looking thing on it.
一样的东西。
And well, he also offered a beautiful heart-shaped pendant.
嗯，他还推荐了一个漂亮的爱心形吊坠。
Okay.
好的。
A pendant is a kind of necklace.
吊坠是一种项链。
And basically a pendant is something that hangs down.
基本上，吊坠是垂下来的东西。
So in this case, it's a necklace that might have something on the bottom that hangs down
所以在这种情况下，它是一条项链，底部可能挂着东西
like in the shape of a heart.
比如心形。
So that's what heart-shaped means.
这就是爱心形的意思。
It means that it has the shape of a heart.
意思是它有心的形状。
Like for example, you can have a heart-shaped cake.
比如，你可以有一个心形蛋糕。
You can also have a heart-shaped face.
你也可以有颗心形脸。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And of course the pendant is a little thing that hangs from the necklace.
当然，吊坠是挂在项链上的小东西。
Now maybe some pendants can also have a gemstone and that's our next word.
现在，有些吊坠可能还带有宝石，这就是我们下一个词。
So a gemstone is not just a normal stone.
所以，宝石不是普通的石头。
It's a beautiful, normally expensive stone.
它是一种漂亮、通常很昂贵的石头。
And we often have gemstones that relate to a person's birthday.
我们经常有与人的生日相关的宝石。
Right.
对。
So these come in many different colors and types.
所以这些宝石有很多不同的颜色和种类。
The two that we heard about in today's dialogue are purple and blue.
我们今天对话中提到的两种是紫色和蓝色。
That's right.
没错。
The purple stone that you're talking about is the one that the shop assistant suggested,
你提到的紫色石头是店员建议的那种，
which is amethyst.
也就是紫水晶。
Amethyst is a purple stone.
紫水晶是一种紫色的石头。
It's really, really pretty and it's sometimes light, sometimes a little bit darker.
它非常非常漂亮，有时颜色浅，有时稍微深一点。
Depends on the one that you're looking at.
取决于你看到的那颗。
But amethyst is a little bit, it's a little bit difficult to say, but it's a kind of gemstone.
但紫水晶有点，有点难说，但它是一种宝石。
The other one we heard about is called topaz.
我们听到的另一种叫托帕石。
Okay.
好的。
A topaz.
托帕石。
And this one is blue.
这个是蓝色的。
So I guess they all look very much like diamonds, but they are different colors.
所以我想它们看起来都很像钻石，但颜色不同。
So topaz looks like a blue diamond kind of.
所以托帕石看起来有点像蓝色钻石。
Right.
对。
And ruby is red.
红宝石是红色的。
Very good.
非常好。
I think there's a black one that's called onyx.
我想有一种黑色的叫缟玛瑙。
Onyx is black.
缟玛瑙是黑色的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So many different types of gemstones.
所以有很多不同类型的宝石。
And as Catherine said, usually each month has a specific gemstone.
正如凯瑟琳所说，通常每个月都有特定的宝石。
So that's considered your gemstone if you were born on that month.
所以如果你出生在那个月，那就是你的生辰石。
Exactly.
正是。
All right.
好的。
Moving on to our next word, we have another type of jewelry that usually hangs from a
继续下一个词，我们有另一种珠宝，通常像吊坠一样挂在
necklace just like a pendant.
项链上。
But on this occasion, it's a locket.
但这次，它是一个小盒坠。
Okay.
好的。
A locket is something that usually women will wear around their necks.
小盒坠通常是女性戴在脖子上的东西。
Now this is like a pendant, but it opens.
这就像吊坠，但它可以打开。
So it's something that can open up.
所以它是一个可以打开的东西。
And sometimes people have photographs inside.
有时人们会在里面放照片。
Many times they're shaped like a heart or a book.
很多时候它们被做成心形或书本形状。
And inside you can see a picture or a note, something very personal.
里面你可以看到一张照片或一张纸条，一些非常私人的东西。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So it's very similar to a pendant, but as you said, it opens up.
所以它和吊坠很相似，但正如你所说，它可以打开。
You see it all the time in movies.
你在电影里经常看到它。
People have pendants and inside they have a nice picture of someone.
人们有吊坠，里面放着某个人的漂亮照片。
That's right.
没错。
So that's a locket.
所以那就是小盒坠。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
I think we've taken a look at a lot of vocab related to jewelry here.
我想我们已经看了很多与珠宝相关的词汇。
Why don't we go back?
我们为什么不回去呢？
Let's review this dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们回顾一下这段对话，我们一会儿回来。
Good afternoon, sir.
下午好，先生。
Is there anything I can help you with today?
今天有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yeah, I'm looking for a nice gift to give my girlfriend.
是的，我在找一份好礼物送给我女朋友。
Our fifth anniversary is next Friday.
下周五是我们五周年纪念日。
Well, I would be happy to assist you in choosing the perfect gift for her.
嗯，我很乐意帮您为她挑选完美的礼物。
Is there anything in particular that you have in mind?
您心里有什么特别的想法吗？
No, not really.
不，没有。
I'm completely at a loss.
我完全不知所措。
Well, you can give her a set of pearl earrings or this beautiful heart shaped pendant.
嗯，您可以送她一套珍珠耳环或这个漂亮的心形吊坠。
What is her favorite gemstone?
她最喜欢的宝石是什么？
That purple one.
那个紫色的。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I've never bought jewelry for anyone and I'm kind of nervous.
我从没给任何人买过珠宝，有点紧张。
Don't worry.
别担心。
We specialize in providing our customers a relaxed, pressure-free shopping environment.
我们专为顾客提供轻松、无压力的购物环境。
That stone is an amethyst.
那块石头是紫水晶。
We have a range of beautiful amethyst pieces.
我们有一系列漂亮的紫水晶饰品。
Take a look at this bracelet.
看看这个手链。
It's 18 karat rose gold studded with amethyst and blue topaz.
它是18K玫瑰金，镶嵌紫水晶和蓝色托帕石。
It's a great statement piece.
这是一件很棒的抢眼单品。
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
That's really pretty.
那真的很漂亮。
Jess would love that.
杰丝会喜欢的。
But I was thinking of something a little more delicate, perhaps a necklace?
但我在想更精致一点的东西，也许是一条项链？
We have this beautiful platinum pendant or you could also get her a locket.
我们有这条漂亮的铂金吊坠，或者你也可以给她买个挂坠盒。
You could also get her a timepiece.
你也可以给她买一块手表。
It's both glamorous and functional.
它既迷人又实用。
If you tell me a little more about your girlfriend, maybe I can help you find something for her.
如果你多告诉我一些关于你女朋友的事，也许我能帮你找到适合她的东西。
Jess?
杰丝？
Well, she's very smart.
嗯，她很聪明。
She's a great sense of humor.
她很有幽默感。
She's very feminine.
她很有女人味。
Perhaps you could give her a ring.
也许你可以给她一枚戒指。
Well, actually, I was thinking about asking Jess to marry me.
嗯，其实，我在考虑向杰丝求婚。
I've just been so nervous.
我一直很紧张。
Well, sir, I believe your fifth anniversary is a great time to propose.
先生，我认为你们的五周年纪念日是求婚的好时机。
Okay, I've decided.
好吧，我决定了。
I'm going to pop the question.
我要求婚了。
Fabulous.
太棒了。
We should look at engagement rings then.
那我们该看看订婚戒指了。
Now, that's a whole other section.
那完全是另一个区域了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at Fluency Builder.
现在让我们来看看“流利度构建”部分。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
So the first phrase in Fluency Builder today comes from the beginning of our dialogue where
今天“流利度构建”的第一个短语来自我们对话的开头，其中
Mark says to the shop assistant, listen, I'm completely at a loss.
马克对店员说：“听着，我完全不知所措。”
Okay.
好的。
So what does he mean when he told the shopkeeper, I'm completely at a loss?
那么他对店员说“我完全不知所措”是什么意思呢？
At a loss means I have no idea.
“不知所措”意思是“我不知道”。
I'm really confused.
我真的很困惑。
Okay.
好的。
All right, I need help.
好吧，我需要帮助。
So if a teacher asks you a question and you don't know the answer, you can say, I'm sorry,
所以如果老师问你一个问题，你不知道答案，你可以说：“对不起，
I'm at a loss.
我不知所措。”
我不知所措。
Or when I see someone and they say, hi, how you doing?
或者当我见到某人，他们说：“嗨，你好吗？”
They say, oh, I'm so embarrassed.
他们说：“哦，我太尴尬了。”
I'm really at a loss.
我真的不知所措。
I don't remember your name.
我不记得你的名字了。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So I'm at a loss.
所以我不知所措。
Now when Mark was describing his girlfriend, Jess, he said, well, she's very smart and
当马克描述他的女朋友杰丝时，他说：“嗯，她很聪明，
has a great sense of humor.
而且很有幽默感。”
Okay.
好的。
So sense of humor is a characteristic that we give to people.
所以“幽默感”是我们用来形容人的一个特征。
So he has no sense of humor or she has a great sense of humor.
所以“他没有幽默感”或“她很有幽默感”。
And this means that this person likes to tell jokes and is funny and enjoys a good time
这意味着这个人喜欢讲笑话，很风趣，并且真正享受
really.
快乐时光。
So does it mean that this person is not really that serious or always angry or unhappy?
那是不是说这个人不是那么严肃，或者总是生气或不开心？
No, not an overly serious person.
不，不是过于严肃的人。
It generally means that the person is good at telling jokes and makes you laugh.
通常意味着这个人擅长讲笑话，能让你笑。
Okay.
好的。
So Jess has a good sense of humor and because of all these things and they've been together
所以杰丝很有幽默感，而且因为这些原因，他们在一起
for five years, Mark says, okay, I've decided I'm going to pop the question.
已经五年了，马克说：“好吧，我决定了，我要求婚了。”
Okay, this might sound very strange because you think, well, pop the question.
好的，这听起来可能很奇怪，因为你会想：“嗯，‘提出那个问题’。”
What is the question?
那个问题是什么？
Well, in English, the phrase pop the question has a very special meaning.
在英语中，“提出那个问题”这个短语有非常特殊的含义。
Means to ask someone to marry you.
意思是向某人求婚。
So if I say I'm going to pop the question, that means I'm going to ask someone to marry
所以如果我说“我要提出那个问题”，意思是我要
me.
向某人求婚。
That's right.
没错。
Or you could say he popped the question last night.
或者你可以说：“他昨晚求婚了。”
We're engaged.
我们订婚了。
Okay.
好的。
So that means?
那意思是？
He asked me to marry him.
他向我求婚了。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
好吧。
So it's a phrase to pop the question.
所以这是一个短语“提出那个问题”。
So whenever you use it together, you're talking about asking someone to marry you.
所以每当你一起使用它时，你就是在谈论向某人求婚。
Exactly.
正是。
All right.
好吧。
Great stuff.
很棒的内容。
Let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
让我们最后再听一遍这段对话。
Good afternoon, sir.
下午好，先生。
Is there anything I can help you with today?
今天有什么可以帮您的吗？
Um, yeah, I'm looking for a nice gift to give my girlfriend.
嗯，是的，我在找一份好礼物送给我女朋友。
Our fifth anniversary is next Friday.
下周五是我们的五周年纪念日。
Well, I would be happy to assist you in choosing the perfect gift for her.
我很乐意帮您为她挑选完美的礼物。
Is there anything in particular that you have in mind?
您心里有什么特别的想法吗？
No, not really.
不，不太确定。
I'm completely at a loss.
我完全不知所措。
Well, you can give her a set of pearl earrings or this beautiful heart-shaped pendant.
嗯，你可以送她一套珍珠耳环，或者这个漂亮的心形吊坠。
What is her favorite gemstone?
她最喜欢的宝石是什么？
That purple one.
那个紫色的。
I'm sorry.
抱歉。
I've never bought jewelry for anyone and I'm kind of nervous.
我从来没给别人买过珠宝，有点紧张。
Don't worry.
别担心。
We specialize in providing our customers a relaxed, pressure-free shopping environment.
我们专为顾客提供轻松、无压力的购物环境。
That stone is an amethyst.
那块石头是紫水晶。
We have a range of beautiful amethyst pieces.
我们有一系列漂亮的紫水晶饰品。
Take a look at this bracelet.
看看这款手链。
It's 18-karat rose gold studded with amethyst and blue topaz.
它是18K玫瑰金，镶嵌紫水晶和蓝托帕石。
It's a great statement piece.
这是一件很抢眼的饰品。
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
That's really pretty.
真漂亮。
Jess would love that.
杰丝会喜欢的。
But I was thinking of something a little more delicate, perhaps a necklace?
但我想要更精致一点的，比如项链？
We have this beautiful platinum pendant or you could also get her a locket.
我们有这款漂亮的铂金吊坠，或者你也可以送她一个挂坠盒。
You could also get her a timepiece.
你也可以送她一块手表。
It's both glamorous and functional.
既时尚又实用。
If you tell me a little more about your girlfriend, maybe I can help you find something for her.
如果你多告诉我一些关于你女朋友的事，也许我能帮你找到适合她的东西。
Jess?
杰丝？
Well, she's very smart.
嗯，她很聪明。
She's a great sense of humor.
她很有幽默感。
She's very feminine.
她很有女人味。
Perhaps you could give her a ring.
也许你可以送她一枚戒指。
Well, actually, I was thinking about asking Jess to marry me.
嗯，其实我在考虑向杰丝求婚。
I've just been so nervous.
我一直很紧张。
Well, sir, I believe your fifth anniversary is a great time to propose.
先生，我认为你们的五周年纪念日是求婚的好时机。
Okay, I've decided.
好吧，我决定了。
I'm going to pop the question.
我要求婚了。
Fabulous.
太棒了。
We should look at engagement rings then.
那我们该看看订婚戒指了。
Now, that's a whole other section.
那是另一个区域了。
So talking about jewelry and all of these gemstones, we also took a look at different
说到珠宝和这些宝石，我们还看了不同的
metal types.
金属类型。
We talked about gold, which is I think one of the most popular types of metals.
我们谈到了黄金，我认为这是最流行的金属之一。
That's right.
没错。
It's kind of like a yellow color.
它有点像黄色。
Now, when we talk about gold, we talk about 14 karat, 18 karat, 24 karat, stuff like this.
说到黄金，我们会提到14K、18K、24K之类的。
Yeah.
嗯。
So the karat, usually it's abbreviated like a K, 18K, 14K.
所以Karat，通常缩写为K，比如18K、14K。
It means how pure the gold is.
它表示黄金的纯度。
Okay.
好的。
And actually, they also use it in diamonds.
实际上，钻石也用这个单位。
They talk about a diamond that's one karat or two karats.
他们会说一克拉或两克拉的钻石。
Right.
对。
So in diamonds, it has a different meaning.
所以在钻石中，它有不同含义。
It actually means how much the diamond weighs.
它实际上表示钻石的重量。
So some engagement rings are half a karat or a karat.
所以有些订婚戒指是半克拉或一克拉。
And the really, really, really big ones are like two karats, and those are very expensive.
而那些非常大的是两克拉，非常贵。
That's right.
没错。
And we also saw another metal here, platinum, which is a very nice metal.
我们还看到了另一种金属，铂金，这是一种很好的金属。
It looks like silver, but it's stronger.
它看起来像银，但更坚固。
It's much stronger, so you can hit something and it won't leave an impression.
它坚固得多，所以敲打它不会留下痕迹。
It won't change the look of the metal.
不会改变金属的外观。
And this is very popular right now for wedding bands.
现在这在婚戒中非常流行。
You know those rings that men and women get after they're married?
你知道男女结婚后戴的那种戒指吗？
Many people like to get this silvery-looking platinum ring.
很多人喜欢这种银白色的铂金戒指。
I've actually seen different types of metals that weren't mentioned in the dialogue, like
我其实见过对话里没提到的不同金属，比如
titanium rings.
钛戒指。
Titanium is also a very strong metal.
钛也是一种非常坚固的金属。
I can't remember this metal, but it's used on spacecraft, and it's very, very strong,
我记不起这种金属了，但它用于航天器，非常非常坚固，
stronger than titanium.
比钛还坚固。
I don't know what it is.
我不知道是什么。
And yeah, they also make rings out of it.
嗯，他们也用它做戒指。
But another interesting thing is some people make their own rings, their wedding bands
但另一个有趣的事是，有些人自己做戒指，他们的婚戒
or their wedding rings.
或结婚戒指。
I've seen that.
我见过。
It's a very nice thing to do, I think, because it's meaningful.
我觉得这是件很好的事，因为它有意义。
People like to do it together, and then they have these rings that are very special for
人们喜欢一起做，然后他们就有了这些对他们来说非常特别的
them.
戒指。
So a person that makes jewelry or makes rings is called a jeweler, right?
所以制作珠宝或戒指的人叫珠宝匠，对吧？
A jeweler, that's right.
珠宝匠，没错。
So I have a friend who is a jeweler.
我有个朋友是珠宝匠。
He makes beautiful rings and earrings.
他做漂亮的戒指和耳环。
Okay.
好的。
So not only rings, a person that makes jewelry in general can be called a jeweler.
所以不只是戒指，制作珠宝的人都可以叫珠宝匠。
Exactly.
完全正确。
All right.
好吧。
A very interesting topic, especially for the girls who always love to have rings and diamonds
一个非常有趣的话题，尤其是对那些总是喜欢戒指、钻石的女孩来说。
and necklaces.
还有项链。
Or the boys.
或者对男生来说。
I know some boys really like to get earrings or to have jewelry like a ring.
我知道有些男生真的很喜欢戴耳环或拥有像戒指这样的首饰。
I've never really seen too many guys wearing necklaces, though.
不过我确实没见过太多男生戴项链。
A lot of guys wear cross necklaces, I've seen.
我见过很多男生戴十字架项链。
Or rings, not too many rings.
或者戒指，但戒指不太多。
I don't think it's a big thing.
我觉得这不是什么大事。
Wedding rings?
结婚戒指呢？
Wedding rings, yeah.
结婚戒指，对。
A lot of American guys wear rings.
很多美国男生都戴戒指。
Do you wear them?
你戴吗？
Yeah, I think, well, not a lot, but some do.
嗯，我觉得，不算多，但有些人戴。
So well, obviously it's popular all around and of course we are interested in hearing
所以，显然这在世界各地都很流行，当然我们也很想听听
from you guys.
你们的看法。
So if you have any questions or any other suggestions about this lesson or anything,
所以如果你对这课或任何事有任何问题或建议，
you can always find us at EnglishPod.com.
你随时可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
We hope to see you guys there.
希望在那里见到你们。
All right.
好吧。
Talk to you nuts.
回头聊，各位。